Gerges Hana Farag

Backend PHP Laravel Developer

mailto:gergeshana2023@gmail.com

+2 01142585940

www.linkedin.com/in/gerges-hana/

• Helwan, Egypt

github.com/Gerges-Hana

Military: completely exempt

Objective

Backend: A talented IT professional with passion for tailored solutions seeksthe
position of Web Developer in a thriving, exciting, and growing company. Comes
with Bachelor's degree in computer science and ITI Full stack PHP and +2
years' experience.

Education

- Graduated Faculty of Computers and Artificial Intelligence, Cairo University, Egypt, At Jul2022, Overall grade: Very good (3.18 GPA), Graduation Project Degree (Excellent), IT Department. <u>Certification</u>
- November 2022 March 2023, Full stack Web Development Using PHP, 3-month Program, Intensive Code Camp (ICC), Information Technology Institute (ITI), Ministry of Communications and Information Technology (MCIT). Smart Village Branch, PHP Track. Certification

Experience

- 12/2022 as **Full stack developer** Freelancing | Khamsat.com 2023 Present
- 4/2023 to 10/2023 as Backend developer at Arabnanis (Giza) Fulltime.
- 11/2023 to 4/2024 as Backend developer at Bebrand (Madii) Fulltime.
- 11/2023 to present as Backend developer at X-era (Madii) Fulltime.

Internship

• January -March 2022, **Frontend web development professional** Offered By UDACITY, Ministry of communications and information technology. <u>Certification</u>

- Oct-Des 2021, Web Developers for HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, an online non-credit course authorized by Johns Hopkins University and offered by COURSERA. <u>Certification</u>
- January-November 2021, Full stack Web Development, 10-month Program, RouteAcademy. <u>Certification</u>

Technical Skills

- Frontend developer
 - HTML, HTML 5, CSS,
 - o Ajax, Json, API
 - o Bootstrap,jQuery
 - o JavaScript,ES6
 - \circ 00P

- Backend Developer
 - o Database(Mysql, SQL by Xampp
 - o PHP
 - o Laravel
 - o GraphQl
 - o API
 - WordPres
 - o Git Hub

PROJECTS

- o **ESACE** (API APP: This is the application for booking cars and how to display my car for work or rental, through the API Auth Api -SMS -mail-smtp-import & export excel -pdf -reports-charts -small ERP system
- O **Restaurants (API_dashboard:** This is a system for managing a restaurant in terms of users, branches, employees, delivery processes, orders, and the cases that aremade according to the change in the condition of Mosul. https://github.com/Gerges-Hana/RestaurantProject **view**
- O **ApiServiceProject(API_dashboard:** This system was working to manage the delivery workers by taking invoices from the contracting companies and distributing them to the company'sdelivery workers: https://github.com/Gerges-Hana/ApiServiceProject **view**
- o **Store_Ecommerce(web_dashboard:** An electronic marketing website to store products, sections, user information, and site settings: https://github.com/Gerges-Hana/Laravel E-commerce) **view**
- O Invoices(web_dashboard: Loan collection companies system from banks this is based on invoices taken from banks directed to customers: https://github.com/Gerges-Hana/Invoices) yiew
- o **ACWAD(web_dashboard:** A control panel project for a client from Turkey to manage and follow up on the financial movements of his project to manage all of his chicken selling branches **view**

- o **X-era/storehouse (API & Dashboard)**: A project to manage the stores of companies in various governorates, and determine the internal orders between stores and follow-up of delegates by Api: https://github.com/Gerges-Hana/X-era-1
- o **X-era /Delivery Companies (API & Dashboard):** A legislator to manage loading and unloading operations to and from the stores and follow them from the beginning of the movement until they reach the stores and unload them and leave and follow up on that from the control panel of the official, and an application for the driver and the security man by Api with GraphQl: https://github.com/X-Era-Tech/warehouse-backend
- o x-era / stock of Warehouse (Dashboard MVC):

 Recording and modifying products through Excel files on the database of the huge system
 Git hub: https://github.com/X-Era-Tech/speed-stocks
- o x-era / Employee Shop (API & Dashboard MVC):

 A system for managing our company's employees' purchases with discount rates, managing them and adding them through Excel files and adding them to the system.

 Git hub: https://github.com/X-Era-Tech/employee-shop-backend